The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: Everything make sense?
教授：一切都有道理吗？
Are you guys good with Newton?
你们对牛顿好吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Yes, really?
教授：是的，真的吗？
I'm done.
我受够了。
I'm going home.
我要回家了。
Are you guys good with Karatsuba?
你们和Karatsuba在一起好吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Kara-what?
教授：卡拉-什么？
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
OK, so who is happy with Karatsuba?
好，那么谁对唐津感到满意？
Good.
好。
Who is happy with Newton?
谁对牛顿满意？
Wait.
等待。
I need to ask the other ones, because not enough people--
我需要问其他人，因为没有足够的人
who is not happy with Newton and wants to look over it?
谁对牛顿不满意而想看看呢？
Who wants to look over Karatsuba?
谁想看唐津？
Oh, so you guy are paying attention.
哦，所以你们在注意。
Good.
好。
OK.
All right.
好吧。
So Newton and Karatsuba.
牛顿和唐津
Let's start.
开始吧。
So Karatsuba real fast, and then we'll
所以唐津真的很快，然后我们将
spend more time having fun with Newton.
花更多的时间在牛顿玩。
So suppose we don't know Karatsuba.
因此，假设我们不认识唐津巴。
We want to multiply two numbers.
我们想将两个数字相乘。
What's the method that we learned in elementary school?
我们在小学学到了什么方法？
AUDIENCE: You take the first digit of the first number,
听众：您采用第一个数字的第一位数字，
and then you multiply it by the second number.
然后将其乘以第二个数字。
And then you take the second digit
然后你取第二个数字
and multiply it by the second number, but then you add a 0.
并将其乘以第二个数字，然后添加一个0。
And so on and so forth.
等等等等。
PROFESSOR: So I'll take this digit
教授：所以我用这个数字
and multiply it with this number and write the result down here,
并乘以该数字并将结果写在这里，
right?
对？
So whatever this thing happens to be, 1, 2, 3, 4 times 8,
因此，无论发生什么事1,2,3,4乘以8，
write the result.
写结果。
Then I take 1, 2, 3, 4 times 7 and add the result here
然后我将1、2、3、4乘以7，然后在这里添加结果
and the last digits are 0.
最后数字为0。
1, 2, 3, 4 times 6, two 0s.
1、2、3、4乘6，两个0。
1, 2, 3, 4 times 5, three 0s.
1、2、3、4乘以5，三个0。
Then I add these up and I know that I'm
然后我将它们加起来，我知道
going to get the right result.
将获得正确的结果。
What's the running time for this?
这是什么时间？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So why is it n squared?
那么为什么n平方呢？
AUDIENCE: Because you go through every single thing
听众：因为您经历了每件事
for every digit below.
对于下面的每个数字。
PROFESSOR: Yup.
教授：是的。
So I'll have these partial products here,
所以我这里有这些部分产品，
and I have as many partial products
我有很多局部产品
as digits in the second number.
作为第二个数字中的数字。
So if I have n digits here, I have n partial products.
因此，如果我在这里有n个数字，则我有n个部分乘积。
Each partial product is this first number here multiplied
每个部分乘积是此第一个数字的乘积
by a digit.
一个数字。
So if this guy has n digits, then there
所以如果这个人有n位数字，那么那里
are n digits everywhere here.
这里到处都是n位数字。
And this thing will be 2 n insides actually,
这个东西实际上是2 n内
but we're doing asymptotic, so we don't really
但是我们正在渐近，所以我们不是真的
care about constant factors.
关心恒定因素。
So in the end, you have to add up n numbers.
所以最后，您必须累加n个数字。
All of them are order n in size.
它们的大小均为n阶。
So n times order n squared.
因此，n乘以n的平方。
This is plain old multiplication.
这是普通的旧乘法。
Does anyone know why Karatsuba's better?
有谁知道唐羽为什么更好？
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: You do three multiplications
听众：您要做三个乘法
or something like that?
或类似的东西？
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So, let's go for a simple answer.
所以，让我们去一个简单的答案。
AUDIENCE: It's better.
听众：更好。
PROFESSOR: So the simpler answer is it's faster.
教授：因此，更简单的答案是更快。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: n, n log 2--
教授：n，n log 2--
AUDIENCE: I said better, it's faster.
听众：我说的更好，更快。
PROFESSOR: I mean, some algorithms have the same speed
教授：我的意思是，某些算法的速度相同
but are simpler.
但更简单。
We like this one because it's faster.
我们喜欢这个，因为它速度更快。
It's definitely not simpler.
绝对不是那么简单。
So, it has this running time here.
因此，它具有此运行时间。
Log 2 of 3 is a weird number.
3的Log 2是一个奇怪的数字。
It's somewhere between 1.5 and 2.
它介于1.5和2之间。
So not revolutionary, but it's better than this guy.
所以不是革命性的，但是比这个家伙更好。
OK, why do we get to this?
好吧，为什么我们要这么做呢？
How do we get to this?
我们如何做到这一点？
Does anyone remember the recurrence for it?
有人记得它的复发吗？
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: It's 3 times 2--
听众：是2的3倍
PROFESSOR: You're not remembering it.
教授：您不记得了。
You're cheating.
你在作弊
AUDIENCE: No, I'm not.
听众：不，我不是。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
PROFESSOR: So, let's see why it looks like this.
教授：那么，让我们看看为什么它看起来像这样。
Karatsuba takes 2 numbers that have n digits, splits both
唐津取2个具有n位数字的数字，将两者均分
of them up into two-- n over 2n, n over 2, n over 2, n over 2--
它们分为两个-n超过2n，n超过2，n超过2，n超过2--
and then is able to compute the product of these two numbers
然后能够计算这两个数字的乘积
by only using three multiplications, and then
通过仅使用三个乘法，然后
some additions.
一些补充。
Multiplications are expensive, additions are cheap.
乘法很昂贵，加法很便宜。
So it does three multiplications that are of the form
所以它做三个乘法形式
some number of n over 2 digits multiplied
超过2位数的n的数量相乘
by some number of n over or 2 digits.
超过n或2位数。
And exactly what the multiplications and what
到底是什么乘法和什么
the additions are is, it's interesting to look over it.
除了是，看看它很有趣。
You can look over it, convince yourself that this is correct.
您可以查看一下，让自己确信这是正确的。
Chances are you'll remember for the exam and forget afterwards.
您可能会记得参加考试，之后会忘记。
Please remember this.
请记住这一点。
This is the essence of Karatsuba.
这就是唐津的本质。
And remember Karatsuba, because if you google this,
请记住唐津，因为如果您用Google搜索，
you get the rest.
你得到其余的。
So the multiplications are in the notes.
因此乘法在注释中。
I don't think it makes sense to spend some time on them
我认为花一些时间在他们身上没有意义
and convince you that, yeah, there
并说服你，是的，那里
are three multiplications that will get you that.
三个乘法将为您带来帮助。
Instead, suppose I labeled these as a, b, c, d.
相反，假设我将它们标记为a，b，c，d。
If I evaluate the multiplication as using brute force,
如果我将乘积评估为使用蛮力，
it's a times n over 2b plus c-- sorry, a plus-- no,
是n超过2b加c的倍数-抱歉，一个加号-不，
this isn't good.
这不好
10 to the power n over 2a plus b times 10-- assuming the base
10乘以2a的幂n加b乘以10-假设基数
is ten, if it's not, you replace it-- n over 2 c plus d.
是十，如果不是，则将其替换-2 c加d上的n。
And you get 10 to the n times, I think, ac plus 10
我想你得到10次到n次，交流加10
to the n over 2 times ad plus bc plus bd.
在2次广告中加上n加上bc加上bd。
The problem with this is this is a multiplication,
问题在于这是一个乘法，
multiplication, multiplication, multiplication.
乘法，乘法，乘法。
So this uses four multiplications
所以这使用了四个乘法
of size n over 2 to evaluate the answer one
n大于2来评估答案之一
multiplication of size n.
大小n的乘积
And if I have four multiplications,
如果我有四个乘法，
then the recursion becomes 4t of n over 2 plus o of n.
那么递归就变成2的n加o的n的4t。
So this is t bad of n.
因此，这对n不利。
So if you do this using the recursion tree,
因此，如果您使用递归树来执行此操作，
you're going to see that-- yup, I hear whispers.
您会看到的-是的，我听到了耳语。
n squared.
n平方。
So this isn't useful.
因此，这没有用。
This will give you insight on how to do it,
这将使您了解如何执行此操作，
but if you try to implement it this way,
但是如果您尝试以这种方式实施，
you don't get any speed up.
你没有任何速度。
The insight in Karatsuba is that the guy figured out
唐津的洞察力是那个家伙想通了
how to do this with three multiplications.
如何用三个乘法做到这一点。
OK, makes sense?
好吧，有道理吗？
Is everyone happy with Karatsuba now?
现在每个人都对唐津感到满意吗？
So that multiplying by 10 to the n over 2 is just shifting a?
那么乘以10乘以n等于2就是将a移位？
PROFESSOR: Yup.
教授：是的。
OK.
好。
Very good point.
很好的一点。
So this isn't an actual multiplication.
因此，这不是实际的乘法。
If you have your number, say stored in a python list--
如果您有电话号码，请说存储在python列表中-
so if these are your digits, then
所以如果这些是你的数字，那么
in order to multiply by 10 to the n,
为了将n乘以10
you append 10 to the n 0s at the end.
您在末尾的n 0后面附加10。
0, 0, 0, 0, 0.
0、0、0、0、0。
So, this is append of 0 n times.
因此，这是0 n次附加。
So this is order n, so it counts as an addition, not as
所以这是n阶，所以算作加法，而不是
a multiplication.
乘法。
So, these are free.
因此，这些都是免费的。
These are expensive.
这些很贵。
1, 2, 3, 4.
1 2 3 4
OK.
好。
Who's happy with Karatsuba now?
谁对唐津感到满意？
Let me feel like I did something useful today.
让我觉得我今天做了一些有用的事情。
AUDIENCE: I have a question.
听众：我有一个问题。
PROFESSOR: Yes.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: I didn't fully understand what [INAUDIBLE].
听众：我不完全明白[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: So, I have this number
教授：所以我有这个电话
and I'm splitting it up into 2 halves.
我将其分为两半。
The way split up is I say this is a number of size n over 2,
拆分的方式是我说这是2的n个数
and I have to shift it to the left.
我必须将其向左移动
So n 10 to the power of n over 2 shifts
所以n 10等于n的2次方的幂
it left by n over two digits.
它在两个数字上留下n。
And then I add it to b.
然后将其添加到b。
So this in a sense is just saying
所以这从某种意义上说
that this is the left half, this is the right half.
这是左半部分，这是右半部分。
AUDIENCE: This is actually that same number.
听众：这实际上是相同的数字。
PROFESSOR: Yup.
教授：是的。
It's exactly the same number.
这是完全相同的数字。
OK, so who is happy with Karatsuba now?
好，那么现在谁对唐津感到满意？
AUDIENCE: Wait, but that's four multiplications though.
听众：等等，但这是四个乘法。
PROFESSOR: Exactly.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: That's not three.
听众：不是三个。
PROFESSOR: Exactly.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: But we said there were three.
听众：但是我们说有三个。
PROFESSOR: So, I was saying that this,
教授：所以，我说的是，
if you;re doing it the brute force way, you get four,
如果你用蛮力的方式做的话，你得到四个，
and that is slow.
那很慢。
So what Karatsuba did is he figured out
所以他想出了Karatsuba所做的
the way to do this with just three multiplications.
只需三个乘法即可完成此操作的方法。
So it's not these three.
所以不是这三个。
You have to think a little bit more.
您必须多考虑一点。
But you google it, or you look at the lecture notes,
但是你用谷歌搜索，或者看讲义，
or you think a little bit, then you find out
或稍微想一想，便会发现
the three multiplications that do the trick.
这三个技巧就完成了。
So the difference between this 4 here and this 3
所以这4和这3之间的区别
here is important.
这很重要。
All right, anything else on Karatsuba?
好吧，唐津还有别的吗？
Cool.
凉。
Let's talk about Newton.
让我们谈谈牛顿。
That's the hard stuff.
那是很难的东西。
And let me see how we're doing on time.
让我看看我们的工作情况如何。
OK, doing well.
好，做得好
So does anyone remember the point of Newton?
有人记得牛顿的观点吗？
OK, so I heard an application that
好，所以我听到一个应用程序
lets you compute square roots.
让您计算平方根。
What else does it let you do?
它还能让您做什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK, we have Karatsuba for multiplication.
教授：好的，我们有唐津乘法。
You might be able to do it with Newton.
您可能可以使用牛顿做到这一点。
Probably not going to be faster.
可能不会更快。
But division, definitely.
但是，当然可以。
So square roots and division.
所以平方根和分裂。
So this is why we care about it.
因此，这就是我们关心它的原因。
Now what does it do from a mathy perspective?
现在，从数学角度来看，它有什么作用？
So what's the mathy definition of Newton.
那么牛顿的数学定义是什么。
AUDIENCE: Estimates--
听众：估计-
PROFESSOR: Estimates?
教授：估计吗？
AUDIENCE: The value--
听众：价值-
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So, we have a function.
因此，我们有一个功能。
Suppose it looks like this.
假设它看起来像这样。
So, what Newton helps us do is it
因此，牛顿帮助我们做到的是
helps us find a root of the function.
帮助我们找到函数的根。
And the root is a value x 0 so that f of x 0 equals 0.
根是值x 0，因此x 0的f等于0。
So this is what it does.
这就是它的作用。
So when you want to use Newton, you
因此，当您想使用牛顿时，
have to set up your function in such a way
必须以这种方式设置您的功能
that your answer is a root.
你的答案是根。
OK.
好。
How does Newton work?
牛顿如何工作？
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: You start at some point
听众：从某个时候开始
where you actually know the answer to it,
你真正知道答案的地方，
and then you kind of draw a approximation.
然后您可以得出一个近似值
So you're just drawing a line from the point to the root,
因此，您只是在从点到根画一条线，
and then just incrementing down that line.
然后沿着那条线递增。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So we start at some point, right?
所以我们从某个时候开始吧？
How do we call that point?
我们怎么称呼这一点？
Initial guess.
初步猜测。
Fancy name.
花式名字。
So we have an initial guess for what the root might be.
因此，我们对根可能是一个初步的猜测。
It's not going to be the right answer, because otherwise
这不是正确的答案，因为否则
why am I bothering with this?
我为什么要为此烦恼呢？
But it can be too far off.
但这可能太遥远了。
We'll say that if you're too far off,
我们会说，如果您离得太远，
you're not going to converge or you're not
你不会收敛或者你不会
going to converge fast enough.
会收敛得足够快。
So say we start somewhere here and, we think, you know,
所以说我们从这里开始，我们认为，你知道，
this is pretty close.
这非常接近。
It's not quite there, but it's pretty close.
它不完全存在，但是非常接近。
What I do from here on is, you said
我从现在开始所做的是，你说
I approximate this function--
我估计这个功能-
AUDIENCE: The line.
听众：这条线。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So what's of the best line?
那么最好的路线是什么？
The best way to approximate the function
近似函数的最佳方法
with the line is to use is the tangent, right?
用的线是切线，对吗？
So here, it sort of looks like this.
所以在这里，它看起来像这样。
And if the function were linear, this
如果函数是线性的，这
would be a perfect approximation and we'd
将是一个完美的近似值，我们会
get answer in one step.
一步就能得到答案。
OK.
好。
So this is the tangent.
所以这就是切线。
And then what we do with this tangent?
然后我们如何处理这个切线？
AUDIENCE: Well, after we get the equation for it,
听众：嗯，我们得到方程式之后，
then we find the root, right?
那我们找到根了吧？
Or no?
或者没有？
PROFESSOR: Well, I can't find the root right away.
教授：好吧，我找不到马上的根源。
AUDIENCE: The root of that line.
听众：那条线的根源。
Of our tangent line.
我们的切线。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So we find the root of the tangent, which
所以我们找到切线的根
is the point where it hits the x-axis.
是它撞击x轴的点。
And what happens with this point?
那么这会发生什么呢？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK, so this is our next guess.
教授：好的，这是我们的下一个猜测。
And then we trade.
然后我们进行交易。
So then we draw another tangent, and the idea
所以我们再画一条切线
is that eventually, you're going to get there.
最终，您将到达那里。
And if we go through the maths, we
如果我们通过数学，我们
will see that you actually get there pretty fast.
将会看到您实际上到达那里的速度非常快。
So that's why we like this method.
这就是为什么我们喜欢这种方法。
So let's see how we convert this drawing thing into an equation
因此，让我们看看如何将绘图内容转换为方程式
that you can write into python.
您可以将其写入python。
Let's label these quantities.
让我们标记这些数量。
So, x2, x1-- actually let's not use 1 and 2,
因此，x2，x1-实际上我们不使用1和2
because these are the first two guesses.
因为这是前两个猜测。
Let's say our current guess is x and the next guess is x prime.
假设我们当前的猜测是x，下一个猜测是x素​​数。
So this line and is x1 minus x, so this guy over here.
所以这行是x1减去x，所以这个家伙在这里。
And what's this guy over here?
那这个家伙是什么？
f of x.
x的f。
Don't be shy.
别害羞
It's the right answer.
这是正确的答案。
So I have f of x here, x 1 minus x here.
所以我在这里有x的f，x是1减去x。
I also have this angle here, and this angle here
我这里也有这个角度，这里也有这个角度
is the same angle as the angle here
与这里的角度相同
because both of these lines are horizontal,
因为这两条线都是水平的，
so they're parallel.
所以它们是平行的。
So what do I know about this angle?
那么我对这个角度了解多少呢？
AUDIENCE: It's tangent.
听众：切线。
PROFESSOR: It's tangent.
教授：这是切线。
OK.
好。
The tangent, that's called the angle alpha.
切线，即角度Alpha。
What's the tangent of the angle?
角度的切线是多少？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Sorry?
教授：对不起？
AUDIENCE: F of x over x [INAUDIBLE].
观众：F x超过x [音频不清晰]。
PROFESSOR: I think you're trying to give me
教授：我想你是想给我
the formula for x prime.
x素数的公式。
Just the tangent.
只是切线。
AUDIENCE: Oh.
听众：哦。
PROFESSOR: Right?
教授：对吗？
Can someone reassure me?
有人可以安慰我吗？
This is right, right?
是这样吧
[AUDIENCE AGREES]
[听众同意]
AUDIENCE: I was thinking the slope of the line.
听众：我在想线的斜率。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So, yeah, you're going to give me
所以，是的，你要给我
the slope of the line which lets me compute this.
线的斜率，让我可以计算出来。
OK, I was looking for this.
好，我在找这个。
OK.
好。
So now, let's get what you're saying.
所以现在，让我们明白您的意思。
So this is the tangent, right?
这就是切线，对吗？
So, the tangent at a point of a function
因此，函数某点的切线
is the function's derivative.
是函数的导数。
So now we're going to write all these things down and hope
所以现在我们要写下所有这些东西，并希望
that we get an equation that make sense.
我们得到了一个有意义的方程。
So we have the tangent of this guy,
所以我们有这个人的切线，
also happens to be this over this.
也恰好是这个。
Right?
对？
This is a right angle triangle, so the tangent
这是一个直角三角形，所以切线
is f of x over-- this is what you
是x的f-这就是你
were trying to tell me, right?
试图告诉我，对吧？
x1 minus x.
x1减x。
So now I know that this is f prime of x.
所以现在我知道这是x的f素数。
OK.
好。
So, we look at the picture, we put in everything we know,
因此，我们查看图片，放入我们知道的所有内容，
and then we write an equation here.
然后在这里写一个方程式
And we solve for-- sorry, this is x prime.
我们解决了-抱歉，这是x质数。
So, if we solve for x prime, we're
所以，如果我们求解x素数，
going to get x prime as a function of x.
将得到x素数作为x的函数。
And this tells us, given a guess here,
这告诉我们，这里有一个猜测，
how do we compute the next guess?
我们如何计算下一个猜测？
So once we have an initial guess,
所以一旦有了初步的猜测，
this lets us make the guess better and better
这让我们做出更好的猜测
and better, closer and closer and closer to x0.
更好，越来越接近x0。
So, let's solve this equation reasonably quickly.
因此，让我们合理快速地解决此方程。
x prime minus x equals f prime of x over f of x, so
x素数减x等于x的f之上的x的f素数，所以
x prime is--
x素数是-
AUDIENCE: Does it matter if it's x minus x prime or [INAUDIBLE],
听众：是x减去x素数还是[听不清]，
because technically it's x minus x prime.
因为从技术上讲，它是x减x素数。
PROFESSOR: Yeah, it matters, because you're
教授：是的，很重要，因为您
going to get the wrong sign.
会得到错误的信号。
Which is exactly what I'm about to do here.
这正是我在这里要做的。
AUDIENCE: Oh, OK.
听众：哦，好。
PROFESSOR: So, I'm not going very well, right?
教授：所以，我做得不好，对吗？
This is wrong.
错了
AUDIENCE: Yeah, it's because you flipped your x at your prime--
听众：是的，因为您在素数时翻转了x
AUDIENCE: x minus x prime instead of x prime--
受众群体：x减x素数，而不是x素数-
AUDIENCE: No, I think it's because f prime of x is on top.
听众：不，我认为是因为x的素数在最前面。
It should be on the bottom.
它应该在底部。
In the second-- no, third equation.
在第二个-不，第三个方程式中。
Shouldn't those be flipped?
那些不应该被翻转吗？
Because if you move the subtraction,
因为如果移动减法，
x prime to the left--
x左边的素数
PROFESSOR: f what?
教授：什么？
AUDIENCE: f of x over f minus x instead
观众：x的f超过f减去x
of f prime x over f of x.
f素数x的x超过x的f。
Yeah, there you go.
是的，你去了。
PROFESSOR: OK, so I can do math.
教授：好的，我可以做数学。
OK, so that's one issue.
好，那是一个问题。
There's one more issue.
还有一个问题。
So, there are too many issues here.
因此，这里有太多问题。
Issue number one, this.
第一期，这个。
Issue number two, I got this wrong.
第二期，我错了。
AUDIENCE: Oh, we get a negative number.
听众：哦，我们得到一个负数。
AUDIENCE: 2x minus x prime.
听众：2x减x素数。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So the reason for that is we're going--
所以这样做的原因是我们要-
AUDIENCE: Only if you start from the right, though.
听众：不过，只有从右开始。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: If you start from the left,
听众：如果您从左侧开始，
if your guess is to the left of the actual root,
如果您的猜测在实际词根的左侧，
it may or may not be different.
它可能不同也可能不同。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So our guess should be to the right.
因此，我们的猜测应该是正确的。
So this is x minus x prime.
因此，这是x减去x质数。
So the reason it's x minus x prime, the way you remember
所以它是x减x质数的原因，你记得的方式
this and you don't do the same mistake that I did
这和你没有做我一样的错误
is, you want to walk against the derivative.
是的，您想反对派生。
If you walk in the direction of the derivative,
如果您沿导数方向走，
it's going to move you forward, right?
它将使您前进，对吗？
So, if you go in the direction of the derivative,
因此，如果您朝导数方向前进，
instead of going backwards like this,
而不是像这样倒退
you're going to go forward like this.
您将像这样前进。
So you're going to go away from the solution.
因此，您将远离解决方案。
So, this will take us in the right direction,
因此，这将带我们朝正确的方向前进，
and this means that it's--
这意味着-
OK.
好。
So two ways to remember this.
有两种方法可以记住这一点。
One that you're going against the derivative.
你反对派生的一种。
Another one is that you have your guess
另一个是你有自己的猜测
and you're subtracting something from it.
然后从中减去一些东西。
AUDIENCE: You flipped your primes again.
听众：您再次翻转了素数。
PROFESSOR: Again?
教授：还是吗？
Jesus.
耶稣。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
AUDIENCE: I mean, I agree, the prime looks
听众：我的意思是，我很赞
better on top part of the fraction, but still.
在分数的顶部更好，但仍然如此。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Well clearly, my hand thinks the same thing.
很明显，我的手也有同样的想法。
So this is you'd iterate using Newton.
因此，这是您要使用牛顿进行的迭代。
So the way to remember that the signs are right
所以记住标志正确的方法
is your x is somewhere here, and you
你的x在这里吗
know you have to subtract something from it so it looks
知道你必须从中减去一些东西
like this figure.
像这个数字。
And this actually works in all the cases, turns out.
事实证明，这实际上适用于所有情况。
Our guesses are usually smaller than the actual number,
我们的猜测通常小于实际数字，
and this still works.
这仍然有效。
OK, so let's go over Newton.
好，让我们来谈谈牛顿。
What do we have, or what do we need in order
我们有什么，或者我们需要什么
to make Newton happen.
使牛顿发生。
So we need to be able to evaluate this, right?
因此，我们需要能够对此进行评估，对吗？
So we need to be able to evaluate
所以我们需要能够评估
f over f prime of x for any x that Newton gives us.
对于牛顿给我们的任何x，f超过x的f素数。
And for Newton, this is a black box.
对于牛顿来说，这是一个黑匣子。
So whichever way you use to implement
因此，无论您采用哪种方式实施
this is fine, as long as it works reasonably fast.
只要它工作得相当快，就可以了。
OK, what else do we need to use Newton.
好，我们还需要使用牛顿。
We need to remember this formula Let's start with something
我们需要记住这个公式让我们开始
easy.
简单。
Suppose we want to use it to compute a over b.
假设我们要使用它来计算a over b。
How do I do that?
我怎么做？
What do I need?
我需要什么？
AUDIENCE: You need a line, a tangent line
听众：您需要一条线，一条切线
like you did before.
像以前一样
PROFESSOR: Well, that's already taken care of here.
教授：好了，这里已经解决了。
So we have this, and we know that we'll
所以我们有了这个，我们知道我们会
have to compute this and plug it in here.
必须计算出来并将其插入此处。
So, what do I need to compute a/b using Newton?
那么，我需要使用牛顿计算a / b吗？
So, I need the function, right?
所以，我需要功能，对吗？
This thing.
这东西。
I can't say it's something, I have to figure out what it is.
我不能说这是什么，我必须弄清楚它是什么。
I guess I was confusing because I said assume we have this.
我想我很困惑，因为我说过假设我们有这个。
Well, sorry.
好，对不起。
We don't have this.
我们没有这个。
We need to figure out the function
我们需要弄清楚功能
so we can evaluate this.
因此我们可以对此进行评估。
OK, so we need to come up with the function
好的，所以我们需要提出函数
so we can evaluate that, and what property
所以我们可以评估一下，以及什么属性
does the function need to meet?
功能需要满足吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Yeah, that would be nice, right?
教授：是的，那很好，对吗？
So we want the function so that f of a/b equals 0,
因此，我们希望该函数使a / b的f等于0，
because that's the number that Newton will give us.
因为那是牛顿给我们的电话。
And we also need to be able to compute f over f prime of x
而且我们还需要能够计算x的f素数上的f
without doing any division, right?
不做任何分割，对吗？
If we did the divisions, it doesn't work.
如果我们进行了划分，那就行不通了。
OK, so the first thing we're going to do
好，所以我们要做的第一件事
is we're going to simplify this problem to 1 over b instead
是将这个问题简化为1比b
of a over b, because if you know what's 1 over b,
a以上的b，因为如果您知道b以上的1，
you're going to multiply this by a,
您将乘以a，
and you're going to get a over b.
并且您将获得a以上的b。
Suppose we work with integers and we
假设我们使用整数并且我们
don't want to touch floating point numbers.
不想触摸浮点数。
What would we actually compute?
我们实际上将计算什么？
AUDIENCE: You shift it out, right?
听众：你把它移开了吧？
To get that 0.23, shift now to [INAUDIBLE].
要获得0.23，请立即移至[音频不清晰]。
PROFESSOR: All right, all right.
教授：好的，好的。
So 1 over b.
所以1分以上
Unless b is 1, in which case it's really boring.
除非b为1，否则确实很无聊。
1 over b looks like this.
b上的1看起来像这样。
0 point something.
0点的东西。
This is not an integer number.
这不是整数。
I don't like it.
我不喜欢
So what I do is, I decide that I'm
所以我要做的就是决定
going to need digits of precision,
需要精度的数字，
and I'm going to shift the decimal point
我将移动小数点
right by d digits.
右边是d位数字。
So instead of 0 point something, it's
所以不是0点的东西，而是
d digits here point something else.
此处的d位数字指向其他内容。
How do I do this?
我该怎么做呢？
AUDIENCE: Multiply by 10 to the d?
听众：乘以10到d？
PROFESSOR: Multiply by 10 to the d.
教授：将d乘以10。
So instead of computing 1 over b, 10 to the d over b.
因此，不是在b上计算1，而是在b上计算d的10。
And we call this 10 to the d R in our station notes.
我们将这10称为电台注释中的dR。
So we're going to compute R. Over b multiplied
因此，我们将计算R。乘以b
by a, and then everything divided by R.
乘以a，然后除以R。
So we talked about how you multiply
所以我们谈到了你如何繁殖
by R. How do you divide by R?
用R划分。如何除以R？
So, if I have a number with n digits
所以，如果我有一个n位数字
and I want to divide by 10 to the d, how do I do that?
我想用d除以10，我该怎么做？
AUDIENCE: Shift.
听众：转变。
PROFESSOR: Shift right.
教授：向右移动。
If the number is a python list?
如果数字是python列表？
AUDIENCE: Slice it.
听众：切成薄片。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So kill the last d digits.
因此，杀死最后的d位数字。
So, if I add d digits to the right,
因此，如果我在右侧添加d位数字，
I multiply by 10 to the d.
我乘以10到d。
If I slice the last digits, I divide by 10 to the d.
如果我将最后几位切成片，则将10除以d。
So this is division, this is multiplication.
所以这是除法，这是乘法。
And the reason I care about that is this
我关心这个的原因是
is going to be an easy division, and whenever I have this,
将会很容易地划分，每当我有这个时，
it's an easy multiplication.
这是一个简单的乘法。
OK, now what function am I going to use?
好，现在我要使用什么功能？
Does anyone know?
有人知道吗？
Can I use x minus R over b equals zero?
我可以在b上使用x减去R等于零吗？
AUDIENCE: Sure?
听众：可以吗？
PROFESSOR: Well, so, this is f of x. f prime of x is what?
教授：好吧，这是x的f。 x的f素数是什么？
AUDIENCE: Just negative R over b.
听众：对b负R。
Or no, 1.
还是不，1。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So, f prime of x over--
因此，x的f素数-
AUDIENCE: I think you switched it again.
听众：我想你又改了。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
PROFESSOR: Thank you.
教授：谢谢。
Because I was running ahead, and I was like, OK, this works.
因为我正在向前奔跑，所以我想，这行得通。
Why does it work?
为什么行得通？
OK, so this is going to be x minus R over b, right?
好吧，所以这将是x减去b的R吧？
Can you evaluate this?
你能评价一下吗？
If I can't evaluate this, I already know the answer.
如果我无法对此进行评估，我已经知道答案了。
AUDIENCE: Your prime's not on the bottom one.
听众：您的素数不在最底端。
PROFESSOR: So, it's x minus this divided by 1.
教授：因此，x减去此除以1。
So, it's this.
所以，就是这个。
So then, if you're trying to evaluate this far the guesses
因此，如果您要对此进行评估，那么猜测
that Newton gives you, you can't.
牛顿给你的，你不能。
Because if you could, you'd have the answer already.
因为如果可以的话，您已经有了答案。
So we can't use this function.
因此，我们无法使用此功能。
This is a nice and easy function that doesn't work.
这是一个很好的简单功能，无法正常工作。
So while I erase the board, one minute, someone
因此，当我擦除木板时，一分钟，有人
figure out the right function.
找出正确的功能。
Sorry?
抱歉？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Man, that's hard math.
教授：天哪，这很难算。
No, that's too hard.
不，太难了。
That's too hard.
太难了
OK, let's try this.
好的，让我们尝试一下。
Let's try instead of x minus R over b,
让我们代替x减去R减去b，
let's try this 1/x minus b/R. And the intuition behind this
让我们试试这个1 / x减去b / R。而这背后的直觉
is if I have to compute b/R, I can do that.
如果我必须计算B / R，我可以做到。
Right?
对？
It's an easy division.
这是一个容易的部门。
If I somehow get rid of 1/x and all I have to do
如果我以某种方式摆脱了1 / x，我所要做的就是
is compute b/R, it's an easy division.
计算b / R，这很容易除法。
Because dividing by 2 to the R by R means
因为用R除以2等于R
you're going to shift by some digits to the right.
您将向右移动一些数字。
So let's see if the math works out for this function.
因此，让我们看看该函数的数学公式是否可行。
What's f prime of x?
x的f素数是多少？
AUDIENCE: Negative 1 over x prime?
听众：x底数上的负数1？
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
Like, does no one know it?
就像，没人知道吗？
At least one student has to know it.
至少一名学生必须知道这一点。
OK, so f of x divided by f prime of x is what?
好，那么x的f除以x的f素数是什么？
AUDIENCE: Negative x plus x squared b/R.
观众：负x加x平方的B / R。
PROFESSOR: Plus x squared b R.
教授：加x平方bR。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: Is this right?
教授：对吗？
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So if I have my initial guess-- so if I want to get x prime,
所以，如果我有最初的猜测-如果我想获得x素数，
x prime is x minus f of x over f prime of x, right?
x素数是x减去x的f等于x的f素数，对吗？
So, what is it?
那是什么
AUDIENCE: 2x minus x squared over R. OK.
听众：R的2x减x平方。确定。
Did this work?
这个工作了吗？
Did it get rid of all the hard divisions?
它摆脱了所有艰难的分歧吗？
[LAUGHS]
[笑声]
Please nod so I know we're good to go.
请点头，我知道我们很好。
Tell me if we're not.
告诉我是否不是。
So how many divisions did we have here?
那么我们这里有多少个部门？
One division, this guy, right?
一师，这个人，对不对？
AUDIENCE: But that's a shift.
听众：但这是一个转变。
PROFESSOR: That's a shift.
教授：那是一个转变。
Because R is 10 to the d.
因为R是d的10。
AUDIENCE: What about the multiplication [INAUDIBLE]?
听众：乘法[音频不清晰]？
PROFESSOR: So, we know how to do multiplication
教授：所以，我们知道如何进行乘法
because we learned Karatsuba just now.
因为我们刚刚才学了唐津
So we wanted to get rid of division,
所以我们想摆脱分裂，
because if you're trying to solve division
因为如果您要解决除法问题
by doing division, it's probably not
通过除法，可能不是
I'm going to work unless you're doing divide and conquer.
除非您要分而治之，否则我将继续工作。
OK, so this is how it works.
好的，这就是它的工作方式。
I'm not going to run into the error formulas for this
我不会碰到这个错误公式
because I want to do another case first.
因为我想先做另一种情况。
You can keep going on this and it's in the notes.
您可以继续进行操作，它在注释中。
The only thing that is useful to remember
唯一有用的记忆
is that we use this trick.
是我们使用了这个技巧。
So, I want to look at this function, square root 3 of a,
所以，我想看看这个函数，a的平方根3，
and I want to use Newton to compute it.
我想用牛顿来计算
So this is the third order root.
因此，这是三阶根。
It's not the regular square root that we had before.
它不是我们以前拥有的规则平方根。
So we're trying to not be boring and not
因此，我们试图不感到无聊和不
just repeat what's in the notes.
只需重复笔记中的内容即可。
How do I do this?
我该怎么做呢？
Let's walk through the steps.
让我们逐步进行。
So what's the first thing that we do?
那么，我们要做的第一件事是什么？
Very good.
很好。
Look to the right.
向右看。
Find the first step, and let's put it here.
找到第一步，然后放到这里。
What's the first step.
第一步是什么。
AUDIENCE: Function f of 0 at cube root of a.
听众：函数f在a的立方根处为0。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So we need a function f so that f of-- good.
所以我们需要一个函数f，以便f很好。
So before we start writing the actual function,
因此，在我们开始编写实际功能之前，
what if I want to compute cube root
如果我想计算立方根怎么办
of a up to d digits of precision?
高达d位的精度？
So if I want to compute cube root of 2,
所以如果我想计算2的立方根
this is going to give me numbers that are below 1.
这会给我小于1的数字。
I have to do with fractions again.
我必须再次处理分数。
I don't like that.
我不喜欢
If I want the digits of precision, what do I do?
如果我想要精度数字，该怎么办？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Jumping ahead.
教授：向前走。
But yeah.
但是，是的。
So you have the right answer, but you're speaking slowly
所以您有正确的答案，但说话速度很慢
because you're afraid you're going to do a mistake, right?
因为您担心自己会犯错，对吗？
So, the way to compute this to d digits of precision 10
因此，将其计算为精度为10的d位数字的方法
to the d, right?
到d吧？
This shifts the dot to the right.
这会将点向右移动。
So I have to get this 10 to the d inside here,
所以我必须把这10送到这里的d
and I get and to the 3d times a.
然后我到达了3d次。
Perfect answer, by the way.
顺便说一句，完美的答案。
Don't forget this 3 here.
不要忘记这里的3。
If you do, you're going to get something else.
如果这样做，您将获得其他好处。
So now I take this guy, and this is the new number
所以现在我带这个人，这是新号码
whose cube root I have to compute.
我必须计算其立方根。
Cube, cube, cube.
多维数据集，多维数据集，多维数据集。
OK.
好。
So I can do this in integer land,
所以我可以在整数范围内执行此操作
and then I'll get an integer result,
然后我得到一个整数结果，
and I shift it right by d digits,
然后将其右移d位，
and I have a number with d digits of precision.
我有一个精度为d位数的数字。
Does this make sense?
这有意义吗？
OK, what's f?
好吧，那是什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Let's go for that.
教授：我们去吧。
Let's see if that works.
让我们看看是否可行。
x cubed minus a.
x减a的立方
Well, let's pretend.
好吧，让我们假装。
We're going to make this b the new a.
我们将使这个b为新a。
So let's not to worry about this.
因此，我们不必为此担心。
This happens somewhere else.
这发生在其他地方。
We went through it so that we know
我们经历了它，以便我们知道
that we know how to deal with it.
我们知道如何处理它。
And now we're going to forget about it.
现在我们将忘记它。
So, it's x cubed minus a.
因此，它是x减a的立方。
Because we argued that this is an integer, right?
因为我们认为这是整数，对吗？
So we don't have to do anything fancy like dividing by R
因此，我们不必做任何花哨的事，例如除以R
that we had to do over there.
我们必须在那里做。
So, what's f prime of x?
那么，x的f素数是多少？
OK.
好。
So, iteration?
那么，迭代呢？
How do we iterate?
我们如何迭代？
AUDIENCE: x prime?
听众：x素数？
PROFESSOR: Let's start with x prime equals
教授：让我们从x素数开始
x minus f of x over f prime of x.
x减去x的f超过x的f素数。
Right?
对？
Nice and easy so we have it here.
很好，很容易，所以我们在这里。
And this becomes minus copy these two things, right?
这变成减去这两件事吧？
x cubed minus a over 3x squared.
x立方减去a超过3x平方。
OK.
好。
Next thing, I bring this guy under the denominator,
接下来，我把这个家伙带到分母的下面，
so it's 3x cubed minus x cubed plus a over 3x squared.
因此是3倍的立方减去x的立方，再加上3倍的平方。
So it's 2x cubed plus a over 3x squared.
因此，它是2倍的立方，再加上3倍的平方。
So this is 2/3 plus--
所以这是2/3加-
AUDIENCE: 2 over 3x.
观众：2倍于3倍。
You keep saying cubed and writing 2.
您一直在说立方体并写作2。
PROFESSOR: Yeah, that's better.
教授：是的，这样更好。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Plus 1/3 times a over x.
加1/3倍于x。
So this one's division.
所以这个人。
AUDIENCE: x squared.
听众：x的平方。
PROFESSOR: x squared.
教授：x平方。
Ouch.
哎哟。
So this guy wants division.
所以这个家伙要分裂。
By the time I do this, I better have division ready, right?
到我这样做的时候，我最好已经准备好了部门，对吗？
OK, so that my iteration.
OK，好让我迭代。
x prime is 2/3 x plus 1/3 and a over x squared.
x素数是2/3 x加1/3和一个x平方。
What else do I need?
我还需要什么？
An initial guess would be nice, right?
初步猜测会很好，对吧？
I can't do this if I don't have the first x.
如果我没有第一个x，我将无法执行此操作。
So let's try to think of a starting x that's reasonable.
因此，让我们尝试考虑一个合理的起始x。
The better it is, the faster it's going to be.
越好，它就会越快。
So let's try to come up with something reasonable that
因此，让我们尝试提出一些合理的建议
doesn't require too much thinking or too much.
不需要太多思考或太多。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Too much work.
教授：太多的工作。
I have to compute a square root.
我必须计算平方根。
So what's a?
那是什么？
Let's start with that.
让我们开始吧。
What's an a, right?
什么是a，对不对？
So, it's an n digit number.
因此，它是一个n位数字。
And say the digits are d1, d2, d3, all the way up to dn.
并说数字一直是d1，d2，d3，一直到dn。
So what's a good approximation?
那么有什么好近似的呢？
Well, the first approximation for this?
好吧，对此的第一个近似值？
AUDIENCE: You get a third as many digits.
听众：您得到的数字是三分之一。
PROFESSOR: A third as many digits.
教授：三分之一的数字。
OK.
好。
So something times 10 to the n/3.
大约是n / 3的10倍。
Let's say that something is 1, right?
假设某物为1，对不对？
So this is the first approximation.
因此，这是第一个近似值。
It's the right order of magnitude.
这是正确的数量级。
Do people see why this is a good approximation?
人们看到为什么这是一个很好的近似值吗？
So this number, whatever it is, it
所以这个数字，无论是什么
has to be between 1, 0, 0 0, 0, and 1, 0, 0.
必须介于1、0、0 0、0和1、0、0之间。
OK.
好。
So generally when we do this, what
所以一般来说，当我们这样做时，
we have to have in an approximation
我们必须近似
is the right order of magnitude And maybe the first digit.
是正确的数量级，也许是第一个数字。
If we can figure out the first digit,
如果我们能找出第一个数字，
then we're in a good shape, or something really
那么我们的状态很好，或者真的
close to the first digit.
接近第一个数字。
How would we get the first digit?
我们将如何获得第一个数字？
AUDIENCE: Cube root of the first digit?
听众：求第一个数字的根？
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Sure.
当然。
How do we compute this?
我们如何计算呢？
AUDIENCE: Get a formula?
听众：获取公式？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK, so I'm not going to argue with that.
教授：好的，所以我不会对此争论。
AUDIENCE: I like that.
听众：我喜欢。
PROFESSOR: So I want to reject the recursive argument first.
教授：所以我想先拒绝递归参数。
So this is going to be small, right?
所以这会很小，对吗？
This is going to be 10 if you're working with digits,
如果您要使用数字，则为10，
or if you're a computer, maybe it's 256,
或者如果您是计算机，也许是256，
or maybe it's 2 to the 16 or 2 to the 32.
或者是2到16或2到32。
Not much bigger than that, right?
没有比这大多少了吧？
Pretty small.
很小
So these algorithms really good for big numbers.
因此，这些算法确实适合大量使用。
Algorithms that are complicated but have
复杂但有
nice asymptotic complexity are good for big numbers.
很好的渐近复杂度对大数有好处。
They're awful for small numbers, as in they 10 to 100 times
它们对于少量数字非常可怕，例如10到100次
more times to run.
运行更多次。
So let's not to do that for this,
所以我们不要为此做，
because it's like bringing a tank
因为就像带一辆坦克
and shooting it so you can hammer a nail in.
然后射击它，以便您可以钉入钉子。
Not the right tool.
不是正确的工具。
So, precomputed list.
因此，预计算列表。
I like that.
我喜欢。
It's an option, especially if you're [INAUDIBLE] right?
这是一个选择，特别是如果您[音频不清晰]对吗？
You can use pen and paper to get it.
您可以使用笔和纸来获取它。
What if I don't want to do that.
如果我不想这样做怎么办。
What if my base is more like this.?
如果我的基地更像这样呢？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: So this is a very good solution.
教授：这是一个很好的解决方案。
I'm not arguing with it.
我不反对。
If your power is this or this, by all means, use a table.
如果您的力量是这个，或者一定要使用这张桌子。
So let's see what do we do here?
那么，让我们看看我们在这里做什么？
I just want to think a little bit more.
我只想多想一点。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK, so there's some approximation
教授：好的，有一些近似值
that comes from math that says that d1 over 3
从数学上得出d1超过3
is not going to be such a bad guess.
不会是一个糟糕的猜测。
Now let's be CS people and do something better.
现在让我们成为CS人才，做得更好。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] the exponent.
听众：[听不清]指数。
2 to the 14, divide-- is that 14, right here
2到14，除以-是14，就在这里
AUDIENCE: 16.
听众：16。
Divide 16 by 3.
用16除以3。
Or I guess that's not quite right either.
或者我想那也不是很正确。
PROFESSOR: So you're saying 2 to the power of, say, 5?
教授：所以您说的是2的幂，例如5？
15 over 3?
15超过3？
AUDIENCE: It doesn't seem quite right.
听众：似乎不太正确。
PROFESSOR: So, let's try to do better.
教授：那么，让我们尝试做得更好。
This is math.
这是数学。
Let's just try to do it in a CS way.
让我们尝试以CS方式进行操作。
So we're trying to guess a digit between 0 and 2 to the 16.
因此，我们尝试猜测0到2到16之间的数字。
I heard an "oh."
我听到一个“哦”。
Yes?
是？
You had your hand up?
你举手了吗？
No?
没有？
OK.
好。
AUDIENCE: You take the current time 2 to the 16.
听众：您将当前时间2改为16。
I mean--
我的意思是 -
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
PROFESSOR: So your algorithm is going
教授：所以您的算法正在发展
to be fast with some probability, right?
一定要快点吧？
No, that's terrible.
不，那太可怕了。
Let's not do that.
我们不要那样做。
Please don't make me grade code like that.
请不要让我这样的成绩代码。
AUDIENCE: Did you already cut out the recursive option?
听众：您是否已经删除了递归选项？
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
Well, so I don't want to recurse on square roots.
好吧，所以我不想递归于平方根。
AUDIENCE: But you could recurse on that one.
听众：但是您可以对此进行递归。
PROFESSOR: I mean, if you give me
教授：我是说，如果你给我
some algorithm that happens--
发生的一些算法-
AUDIENCE: You're already [INAUDIBLE].
听众：您已经[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So, what's the intuition?
那么，直觉是什么？
If you have a computer and you have register,
如果您有一台计算机并且已经注册，
bytes, bits, whatever.
字节，位等。
You don't know how to do square roots.
您不知道如何做平方根。
That's not an instruction, but these are all instructions.
那不是指令，但是这些都是指令。
Right?
对？
So if I have a guess, say I start with half
所以如果我有一个猜测，说我从一半开始
and then I get my guess, what do I need for the binary search
然后我猜到了，进行二进制搜索需要什么
to work?
上班？
Given a guess that's somewhere here,
猜想在这里
I have to be able to say whether this is too small, too big,
我必须说这是太小还是太大，
or just the right number.
或正确的号码。
So given a guess, I can multiply it by itself three times,
因此，我可以将其自身乘以三倍，
right?
对？
Compute gets cubed.
计算得到立方体。
And I can see how does it compare to the number
我可以看到它与数字相比如何
that I want.
我想要的。
So I have the first digit, and I have an order of magnitude.
所以我有第一个数字，并且有一个数量级。
Not bad, right?
还不错吧？
Pretty good initial guess.
很好的初步猜测。
This is as much of an answer is you need to give out
这就是答案，您需要给出答案
in physics problems, and you get full score, so that's good.
在物理问题上，您会得到满分，所以这很好。
OK, how are we doing so far?
好，到目前为止我们怎么样？
Following along?
跟着呢？
AUDIENCE: If we compute our guess cubed,
观众：如果我们计算出立方的猜测，
we want only to compare it to our original number
我们只想将其与原始号码进行比较
to see how close it is?
看它有多近？
PROFESSOR: Yup.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: And, do we just keep on doing that until--
听众：而且，我们是否继续这样做直到-
PROFESSOR: Well, so you're going have to guess a digit, right?
教授：好吧，所以您将不得不猜测一个数字，对吧？
Between 0 and 2 to the 16.
在0到2到16之间。
So you choose the largest thing that's smaller than your guess,
因此，您选择比您的猜测小的最大的东西，
or something.
或者其他的东西。
AUDIENCE: Or until we get the first digit.
听众：或者直到我们得到第一个数字。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
Just the first.
只是第一个。
And then you have a first digit, and then you
然后你有第一个数字，然后你
have an order of magnitude.
有一个数量级
And then you feed that to Newton,
然后把它喂给牛顿，
which converges way faster.
收敛速度更快。
So you could the binary search for the whole thing,
因此，您可以对整个内容进行二进制搜索，
but that would be slower than Newton, turns out.
但事实证明，这将比牛顿慢。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: So where'd you get the f of x here?
听众：那么你在哪里得到x的f？
I'm missing that stuff.
我想念那些东西。
PROFESSOR: Oh.
教授：哦。
AUDIENCE: Yeah, right there.
听众：是的，就在那里。
PROFESSOR: Someone told me to use this.
教授：有人告诉我使用这个。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
One of you guys told me to use this.
你们中的一个告诉我要使用它。
Well, so I tried it out.
好吧，所以我尝试了一下。
I put it here.
我把它放在这里。
And then I computed the derivative,
然后我计算了导数
and I looked to see if this looks reasonable.
我看这看起来是否合理。
And this looks like something I can compute.
这看起来像我可以计算的东西。
AUDIENCE: And why was that reasonable?
听众：那为什么合理呢？
PROFESSOR: Because I know how to do the division
教授：因为我知道该怎么做
and multiplication.
和乘法。
So, say if I would have had the square root of 3 in here,
因此，假设我在这里具有3的平方根，
that wouldn't be reasonable, right?
那是不合理的，对吧？
Just like before.
就像以前那样。
When you're trying to compute division,
当您尝试计算除法时，
we can't have division.
我们不能分裂。
If you're trying to compute sine of x,
如果您要计算x的正弦，
you don't want to have sine of x.
您不想有x的正弦。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
and computing a over x squared is reasonable?
和计算一个x平方是否合理？
PROFESSOR: Because we did it before.
教授：因为我们以前做过。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
So then you might use something else, maybe?
那么，您可能还会使用其他东西吗？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
You can use something else as long as you know how to do it,
您可以使用其他方法，只要您知道该怎么做，
and as long as it's reasonably fast.
并且只要它相当快。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: Yes?
教授：是吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Oh, no that's fine.
教授：哦，那很好。
AUDIENCE: Oh, that fine?
听众：哦，好吗？
OK.
好。
PROFESSOR: So, the binary search is
教授：因此，二进制搜索是
fine to get the first approximation.
可以得到第一近似值。
But after that-- so I'm not going
但是之后-所以我不去
to do a binary search for the whole result,
对整个结果进行二进制搜索，
because Newton is faster than that.
因为牛顿比那快。
I'm just using this so that I have a decent guess
我只是用这个，所以我有一个不错的猜测
to pass to Newton.
传递给牛顿。
And we'll see why we need that decent guess in two minutes
我们将在两分钟内看到为什么我们需要这样的猜测
total.
总。
So I'm going to try to spend two minutes to explain
所以我将尝试花两分钟来解释
how the error thing works, and you'll
错误是如何工作的，您将
have to look at the notes and make sense out
必须看一下笔记并弄清楚
of the rest of it.
其余的。
So, let's see.
所以，让我们看看。
Errors.
错误。
So with Newton, you start to with an initial guess,
因此，对于牛顿，您首先要进行初步猜测，
and then you get to a better guess, and a better
然后你会得到一个更好的猜测，一个更好的
guess, and a better guess, and so on and so forth
猜测，更好的猜测，依此类推
until you're satisfied.
直到您满意为止。
By the way, if we're doing this one, are we satisfied?
顺便说一句，如果我们正在这样做，我们是否满意？
AUDIENCE: What do you mean, like, finding the guess?
听众：寻找猜测是什么意思？
Are we satisfied?
我们满意吗？
PROFESSOR: Oh, no.
教授：哦，不。
So, we have the initial guess.
因此，我们有了初步的猜测。
And we keep applying the formula that I just deleted to iterate.
而且，我们继续应用刚刚删除的公式进行迭代。
When do we stop?
我们什么时候停止？
AUDIENCE: When we have enough digits of precision?
听众：什么时候我们有足够的精度？
PROFESSOR: So how do we know when we have enough digits,
教授：那我们怎么知道什么时候有足够的数字，
if we're working with integers?
如果我们使用整数？
AUDIENCE: We iterate again and nothing changes.
听众：我们再次进行迭代，没有任何变化。
PROFESSOR: We iterate again and nothing changes.
教授：我们再次进行了迭代，没有任何变化。
So I'm computing-- do I have this anywhere?
所以我在计算-我到处都有吗？
Oh, no.
不好了。
I erased it.
我删除了。
So I'm computing 10 t0 some-- oh, I had it up here.
所以我正在计算10 t0-哦，我在这里。
So, I'm computing 10 to the power
所以，我正在计算10
of d times a square root of 3, because I
d乘以3的平方根，因为我
want to work with integers.
想使用整数。
Just integers.
只是整数。
I used Newton to iterate.
我用牛顿来迭代。
My precision gets gets better and better and better.
我的精度越来越好。
And I use integers.
我使用整数。
So I only have d digits of precision.
所以我只有d位精度。
Everything after that gets discarded automatically.
之后的所有内容都会自动丢弃。
When I get 2 x's that don't change-- so if I get x5,
当我得到2 x时，它不会改变-因此，如果我得到x5，
and then I run the thing and then
然后我跑东西，然后
I get x6 that is equal to x5, there's
我得到的x6等于x5，有
no point to keep running Newton, right?
没必要继续跑牛顿吧？
I;m stuck.
我被困住了。
And I'm also done because I have the answer
而且我也完成了，因为我有答案
with d digits of precision.
精度为d位。
So this is where I stop.
所以这是我停下来的地方。
OK.
好。
Now, my precision is how far I am from the right answer.
现在，我的精度是我离正确答案有多远。
And we write that by saying that x1
我们说x1
is x, the true answer, times 1 plus epsilon, epsilon 1.
是x，是真正的答案，乘以1加epsilon，epsilon 1。
And then x2 is x times 1 plus epsilon 2, 1 plus epsilon 3,
然后x2是x乘以1加epsilon 2、1加epsilon 3，
so on and so forth.
等等等等。
Right?
对？
So, if we had a lot of time and not too much stuff to do,
因此，如果我们有很多时间，没有太多事情要做，
I could copy this thing here that we have in the notes.
我可以在笔记中复制此内容。
That's eight lines of math.
那是八行数学。
And then we'd get something along the lines of x of i
然后我们将得到与x相似的东西
plus 1 is x times 1 plus something times E
加1是x乘1加某事乘E
squared-- I'm sorry, Ei squared.
平方-对不起，Ei平方。
So this is also 1 plus Ei plus 1.
所以这也是1加Ei加1。
So what we get is that E of i plus 1 is roughly E i squared.
所以我们得到的是，我的E加1大约等于我的平方。
And this is what's really called quadratic convergence.
这就是所谓的二次收敛。
Now why is this good?
现在为什么这么好？
Can anyone think intuitively why this is nice?
任何人都可以凭直觉思考为什么这很好吗？
In which cases?
在什么情况下？
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: You're converging really quickly to your answer.
听众：您很快就可以收敛自己的答案。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
But when do I converge?
但是我什么时候收敛？
, So what I want this to happen?
，那么我希望这种情况发生吗？
What do I want this to be?
我希望这是什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Well, you guys told me everything
教授：嗯，你们都告诉我了一切
I need for the next two minutes.
接下来的两分钟我需要。
So, I want this to become 1, right?
所以，我希望这个变成1，对不对？
This has to go to 1 because I want this whole thing to be x.
这必须设为1，因为我希望整个东西都是x。
So in order for this to be 1, I want to epsilons to go to 0.
因此，为了使它为1，我想将epsilons设置为0。
So I want them to be as small as possible.
所以我希望它们尽可能小。
Now, you said that if my epsilon is smaller than 1,
现在，您说如果我的ε小于1，
then epsilon squared is smaller than epsilon.
那么epsilon平方小于epsilon。
And intuitively, how this works is,
从直觉上讲，这是如何工作的，
suppose you start with an epsilon of 0.1.
假设您的epsilon为0.1。
When you square it, you get 0.01.
平方时，得到0.01。
You square it again, you get 0.0001.
再次平方，得到0.0001。
Square it again.
再次平方。
0.00000001.
0.00000001。
OK.
好。
This is step 0, step 1, step 2, step 3.
这是步骤0，步骤1，步骤2，步骤3。
How many digits do I have here?
我这里有几位数？
Don't be shy.
别害羞
AUDIENCE: 2 to the i?
听众：2到i？
PROFESSOR: Yup.
教授：是的。
2 to the i.
2到i。
So this is going to be equal to this
所以这将等于
when 1 plus x times 1 plus epsilon i over 1 plus epsilon--
当1加x乘以1加epsilon我超过1加epsilon--
sorry, i plus 1 epsilon i when the floor of this thing
抱歉，我加上1 epsilon我在地板上
is-- sorry, there is a delta somewhere here.
是-抱歉，这儿有一个三角洲。
So, something has to converge to 0.
因此，某些东西必须收敛到0。
Sorry, this is what it is.
抱歉，就是这样。
1 plus e of i.
i的1加e。
So this is the difference between two terms, x.
这就是两个项x的差。
So this is x6 minus x5, right?
所以这是x6减去x5，对吧？
Convincing?
有说服力吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
Let's write it again.
让我们再写一次。
This is out of hand.
这是失控的。
So, x, x minus x5, or actually, xi
因此，x，x减去x5，或者实际上是xi
plus 1 minus xi is equal to x times 1 plus epsilon i
加1减xi等于x乘以1加epsilon i
plus 1 minus x times 1 plus epsilon i, right?
加1减x乘1加epsilon i，对吗？
So this is x times-- Sorry?
这是x次了-对不起？
AUDIENCE: Those are xi, x of i.
听众：那是xi，i的x。
AUDIENCE: No, those are the real x's.
听众：不，那是真实的x。
PROFESSOR: These are-- so these are the approximations,
教授：这些是近似值，
but then, this is the real x.
但这就是真实的x
AUDIENCE: I understand, thank you.
听众：我明白，谢谢。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So, this is, the difference between them is this guy here.
所以，这是他们之间的区别是这个人。
So if I take the floor because I work with integers,
因此，如果我因为使用​​整数而发言，
when this floor becomes 0, we're done, right?
当该楼层变为0时，我们完成了，对吗？
So in order for the floor to become 0,
因此，为了使下限变为0，
this guy has to be canceled by this guy.
这个人必须被这个人取消。
So this guy has some number of digits, whatever that is.
所以这个家伙有一些数字，无论是多少。
It's my number with d digits of precision.
这是我的数字，精度为d位。
Well, that's OK because-- where my 0s?
好吧，那没关系，因为-我的0在哪里？
Did I erase my 0s?
我是否擦除了0？
Oh, no.
不好了。
I have 0s here, right?
我这里有0，对吧？
The epsilons have a lot of 0s in them,
epsilons中有很多0，
so the 0s are going to cancel the digits in x.
因此0将取消x中的数字。
So as soon as I have enough 0s here to cancel this, I'm stuck.
因此，只要我在这里有足够的0来取消此设置，我就会被卡住。
The number of 0s increases exponentially.
0的数量呈指数增加。
So in each step the number of 0s I have doubles.
因此，在每一步中，0的数量都会加倍。
So after log d steps, I'm done.
因此，在完成d步骤之后，我就完成了。
If I have d digits in here, because I'm
如果我在这里有d位数字，因为我
computing this with d digits of precision,
用d位精度进行计算
after roughly log d steps, I'll have enough 0s here
经过大致的记录d步骤，我这里将有足够的0
to reduce this and make the whole thing be 0.
减少这个并使整个东西为0。
So this is how I know that it's fast.
这就是我所知道的快速的方式。
So in the end, what you want is the initial guess
所以最后，您想要的是最初的猜测
has to satisfy this, and then you
必须满足这个，然后你
want to be able to prove that this is true.
希望能够证明这是真的。
So you want this factor here that tells you you're
所以你想要这个因素告诉你
converging fast.
快速收敛。
So when you look at the recitation notes
所以当你看背诵笔记时
and you look at this long string of equations,
然后看一长串方程，
make sure this is somewhere there,
确保这是在那里
because this means you're on the right track.
因为这意味着您走在正确的轨道上。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: If it takes log d steps,
听众：如果需要log d步骤，
doesn't the binary search also take log-- ah, OK.
二进制搜索是否也需要日志-啊，好的。
Log 10 steps.
记录10个步骤。
Got it.
得到它了。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
Which is d.
d。
AUDIENCE: He's talking about binary search--
听众：他在谈论二进制搜索-
PROFESSOR: Oh, for one digit.
教授：哦，一位。
Yeah.
是的
Oh, sorry.
哦对不起。
I thought you meant for the whole thing.
我以为你是整个意思。
So if you wanted to do binary search for the whole thing,
因此，如果您想对整个内容进行二进制搜索，
that's log of the whole number.
那是整数的对数。
So that's order d where d is the number of digits.
所以是d的顺序，其中d是位数。
AUDIENCE: Wait, he's talking about a binary [INAUDIBLE].
听众：等等，他在说二进制文件[听不清]。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] wants to go for [INAUDIBLE], 10
观众：[听不清]想参加[听不清]，10
to the 20th.
到20日
He wants to do a binary search over like a cube root--
他想像立方根一样进行二进制搜索-
PROFESSOR: So, for this?
教授：那么，为此吗？
Binary search for this or for one digit?
二进制搜索这个还是一位？
Or binary search to compute the cube root?
还是二进制搜索来计算立方根？
AUDIENCE: I think, yeah.
听众：我认为，是的。
PROFESSOR: So, if you do that, your entire thing is
教授：所以，如果您这样做，您的整个工作就是
d digits, right?
d位，对吗？
So 10 to the d.
所以10到d。
Binary search takes log of 10 to the d.
二进制搜索将10的对数记为d。
AUDIENCE: Right, yeah.
听众：对，是的。
PROFESSOR: So the numbers that we're
教授：所以我们的数字
dealing with are d digits.
处理的是d位数字。
So this d is the number of digits, not the number
所以这个d是位数，而不是数字
that you have.
你有。
So if you look at the number that you have,
因此，如果您查看所拥有的号码，
this is log log n.
这是日志日志n。
AUDIENCE: Right, that makes sense.
听众：对，这很有道理。
Sorry.
抱歉。
PROFESSOR: So, it's faster.
教授：所以，它更快。
AUDIENCE: I like it.
听众：我喜欢。
It is faster.
它更快。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Cool.
凉。
Thanks for the lesson.
感谢您的教训。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。